

Nathan Birrell

January 2024 | github.com/nathanbirrell | linkedin.com/in/nathanbirrell | nathanbirrell@gmail.com

ABOUT ME:

Software Engineer with 10+ years of technical experience, scaling-up software products and building great teams. Interested in senior front-end roles, full-stack and open to lead roles (remote preferred).

I also enjoy 🏂 surfing, 🚴 bicycles and 🕏 espresso.

KEY SKILLS:

- Specialised frontend experience across React, Typescript, NextJS & CSS
- 2. Strong backend commercial experience with Node, GraphQL, Express, REST, both RDBMS & NoSQL
- 3. Solution architecture on AWS: Lambda, ECS, AppSync, DynamoDB, CDK

Experience

MYOB

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER (CONTRACT) • OCT 2023 - PRESENT

MYOB is an accounting SaaS business. I was brought onto the Web & Content team.

- Key deliverables: support article search with Algolia integration; core web vitals improvements; integration with headless CMS (Contentful) and middleware performance improvements.
- Strategic guidance on architecture decisions (NextJS upgrades, localisation, partial prerendering).

Stax (by Versent)

FRONT-END LEAD (PLATFORM) • NOV 2020 - OCT 2023

Stax is a B2B SaaS AWS cloud management platform, which empowers teams to deliver on AWS with consistency, confidence and velocity. In October 2023, Stax & Versent sold to Telstra for \$267.5m.

- Ownership of long-term strategy for a production frontend application (20k+ LOC), a component library, style system and a backend API service (60k LOC).
- Led architecture/build for a backend-for-frontend project, to simplify interfacing with microservices
- Scaled-up engineering capabilities from 5 engineers to 30+, establishing best practices and processes for our growing organisation.
- Mentored and supported junior engineers, helping them grow their skills and confidence through pair programming, code reviews and leading workshops.
- Tech: Typescript, GraphQL, Apollo, React, Jest, Playwright, NodeJS, AWS Lambda, AppSync, DynamoDB Serverless, SQS, SAM, CDK and more.

Stax (by Versent)

SENIOR FRONT-END ENGINEER • OCT 2018 - 2020

- Set-up best-practice foundations for our React app with unit testing, end-to-end tests, linting, CI processes and docs. Tooling snapshot: NextJS, React, Typescript, GraphQL, Lambda, DynamoDB.
- Increased consistency across multiple frontend projects and across Engineering and Design teams, with a style system and component library.

Bureau of Meteorology

SOFTWARE ENGINEER (CONTRACT) • MAR 2018 - OCT 2018

- A new weather experience for the general public in Australia's top 30 most visited websites
- Improved reliability and protyping speed with static typing & tree-structured state management lib

Belong (by Telstra)

FRONT-END DEVELOPER • NOV 2016 - MAR 2018

Deloitte Digital

UI DEVELOPER (CONSULTANT) • JAN 2014 - NOV 2016

Education

Bachelor of Business (Information Systems)

2012-2015

Royal Melbourne Institute of Technology (RMIT University)